Guide to the New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection TAM.798
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Queens Neighborhoods United Instagram, May 2020-ongoing; Queens Neighborhoods United (Box Electronic Records)
  Queens Neighborhood United (QNU) is a volunteer, activist working group representing the neighborhoods of Jackson Heights, Corona, and Elmhurst. Founded in 2014 by small business owners as an anti-business improvement district organization, QNU "believes in establishing community control over land-use, policing, and immigration policies that directly impact and works to displace us." It accomplishes its work through use of grassroots organizing, direct action, leadership development, advocacy, and community education. Beginning on April 1, 2020, QNU uses its Instagram account to communicate directly to its members and allies around campaigns to support its community during COVID-19. The feed includes still and moving image and calls for support for Elmhurst Hospital, emergency response funds for laundry workers, announcements for know your rights trainings, and actions to support houseless community members. The un-archived Instagram feed includes video of an NYPD arrest of a houseless immigrant man which has not been included in this web archive in accordance with this collection's development policy and in order to preserve that individual's privacy
- Reading the Pictures: Coronavirus, July 2023; Reading the Pictures (Box Electronic Records)
  Photo essays related to COVID-19. Reading the Pictures is a educational and publishing organization dedicated to visual culture, visual literacy and media literacy through the analysis of news, documentary and social media images. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Organizing Toolkit - Rent Strike 2020, June 2020-February 2022; Rent Strike 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. The document calls for a freeze of rent, utilities and mortgage payments; freeze of student, consumer, and medical debt; tax of big business; housing for all unsheltered people; as well as other demands and how to orgainze around the demands.
- Evictions Protections during COVID: Know Your Rights, February 2022-ongoing; Right to Counsel NYC Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  An FAQ created by the Right to Counsel NYC Coalition that explained the New York eviction moratorium under the Tenant Safe Hard Act that was established from March 7, 2020 to January 15, 2022 if the tenant suffered financial hardship due to COVID-19. Also discusses other resources and protections for tenants.
- New York Tenants: Eviction Protections, The Courts, New & Pending Eviction Cases, February 2022-ongoing; Right to Counsel NYC Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document breakdown the executive orders, court directives, and new laws related to evictions, new case filings, and court closures during COVID-19.
- Desiree Rios COVID-19 Coverage for the New York Times, July 2023; Rios, Desiree A. (Box Electronic Records)
  Photographs taken by Desiree Rios for the "'It's Not Enough': Living Through a Pandemic on $100 a Week" article in the New York Times. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The 63106 Project, July 2023; River City Journalism Fund (Box Electronic Records)
  Essays on issues facing St. Louis, MO residents. Part of the River City Journalism Fund. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The Memorialising Covid Episode, July 2023; Rothermere American Institute (Box Electronic Records)
  Podcast episode of The Last Best Hope?: Understanding America from the Outside In, hosted by Adam Smith. The podcast is an initiative of the Rothermere American Institute at the University of Oxford. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Sex Workers Outreach Project Brooklyn, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  Sex Workers Outreach Project (SWOP) is a "peer-led organization supporting and advocating for sex workers in New York." In response to COVID-19 SWOP Brooklyn created a campaign "to provide monetary aid to sex workers in the New York City area who are in critical need of aid." The SWOP Brooklyn COVID web page offers guides and resources to support sex workers during the pandemic, and the SWOP Brooklyn homepage provides regularly updated data on how their funding is being allocated -- largely to individual stipends, but also to outreach and housing for individuals being released from Rikers.
- Accessible Remedials During COVID-19, June 2020-February 2022; Sex Workers Outreach Project Brooklyn (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document detailing accessible remedials for COVID-19 and pneumonia/bronchial infections.
- Chris Smalls (Amazon Strike) Instagram, May 2020-ongoing; Smalls, Chris (Box Electronic Records)
  Christian "Chris" Smalls, a management assistant at Amazon Warehouse JFK98 located on Staten Island, was fired by Amazon on March 30th, 2020 after organizing a strike to call attention to the lack of protections for workers at the facility. Documentation of Smalls' labor and COVID-19 activism begins with a March 30th, 2020 post in which Smalls includes images of the Amazon walkout and a quote from an interview with Smalls in Jacobin magazine. Smalls' Instagram feed includes still image and video posts documenting the walkout, artwork depicting Smalls, calls for action, fundraising campaigns related to supporting striking Amazon workers, and social justice focused events and programming in which Smalls is a participant.
- Christian Smalls Twitter, May 2020-ongoing; Smalls, Chris (Box Electronic Records)
  Christian "Chris" Smalls, a management assistant at Amazon Warehouse JFK98 located on Staten Island, was fired by Amazon on March 30th, 2020 after organizing a strike to call attention to the lack of protections for workers at the facility. Documentation of Smalls' labor and COVID-19 activism begins with a March 30th post in which Smalls records the inside of the JFK98 warehouse break room where social distancing rules are not enforced and workers are without personal protective equipment. Smalls' Twitter feed includes still image and video posts documenting the walkout, artwork depicting Smalls, calls for action, fundraising campaigns related to supporting striking Amazon workers, and social justice focused events and programming in which Smalls is a participant.
- Smithsonian Channel, July 2023; Smithsonian Institution (Box Electronic Records)
  Redirects to Smithsonian Channel homepage. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Crisis brings the Hate, We bring Rainbows, June 2020-February 2022; Talen, Bill (Box Electronic Records)
  CW: This video contains the violent arrest of Reverend Bill Talen, of Reverend Billy and the Church of Stop Shopping, and harmful racist, homophobic, and transphobic language spoken by Franklin Graham of Samaritan's Purse. During the 2020 COVID-19 crisis, Samaritan's Purse - an evangelical organization led by Franklin Graham - constructed a field hospital in Central Park. Given the organization's stance on LGBTQIA issues; homophobic, transphobic, and Islamophobic statements made by Graham; and the organization's requirement that individuals working for Samaritan's Purse must be Christians who oppose same-sex marriage, the hospital was met with criticism by LGBTQIA leaders, progressive religious leaders, and elected officials. LGBTQIA organizations, and others, protested the field hospital, inclusive of this action taken by Reverend Billy, in which he raises a rainbow flag next to the hospital. In May of 2020, the field hospital discharged its patients and dismantled its tents.
- COVID -19 Impact Project, July 2023; Thompson, John Henry; Johnson, Shindy (Box Electronic Records)
  The COVID-19 Impact Project is a crowdsoured platform to contribute ideas, share personal stories, memorialize loved ones, and examine statistics relative to the collective COVID-19 experience. The website contains visualizations on COVID-19 deaths and student projects that "humanize" data. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Judith Butler: Creating an Inhabitable World for Humans Means Dismantling Rigid Forms of Individuality, July 2023; Time, inc. (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Judith Butler in Time Magazine. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Transportation Alternatives- Bike Match, June 2020-July 2021; Transportation Alternatives (Organization) (Box Electronic Records)
  Transportation Alternatives' (TA) mission is to reclaim New York City's streets from the automobile and advocate for better bicycling, walking, and public transit for all New Yorkers. With 100,000 active supporters, TA fights for the installation of infrastructure improvements that reduce speeding and traffic crashes, save lives and improve everyday transportation for all New Yorkers. Since their founding in 1973, TA's work has led to he extraordinary growth of bicycling, the launch of Citi Bike and the introduction of innovations to city streets, like Complete Streets, parking-protected bike lanes, automated speed enforcement cameras, public plazas, Select Bus Service and Neighborhood Slow Zones. TA activists are currently leading the fight to improve infrastructure for bicycling and walking on scores of local streets and to change traffic enforcement policy and practices citywide.
- Marked By Covid, July 2023; Keeves, Christine; Urquiza, Kristin (Box Electronic Records)
  Marked By Covid is the "survivor-led movement for pandemic justice and remembrance." The organization is working toward establishing a COVID memorial day and national memorial, and a call for an investigation of the United States pandemic response. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Memorial Matrix, July 2023; Urquiza, Kristin; Keeves, Christine (Box Electronic Records)
  The Marked by Covid Memorial Matrix is a crowdsourced memorial map and timeline that documents the network of Covid Memorials completed in the United States since the start of the pandemic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Vt. Poet Laureate Mary Ruefle Mails Verse To Vermonters In 'Random Acts Of Poetry', July 2023; Vermont Public (Box Electronic Records)
  Radio story by Mitch Wertlieb and Matthew F. Smith on Vermont Public Radio. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The Ladder Up: A Restless History of Washington Heights, July 2023; Virginia Quarterly Review (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Carina del Valle Schorske in the Virginia Quarterly Review. Photography by Carlos Rivera. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Grieving families asked Congress to recognize covid's victims. It didn't go well., July 2023; Washington Post Company (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by William Wan in the Washington Post. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- One million of us, July 2023; Washington Post Company (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Sergio Peçanha and Yan Wu in the Washington Post. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Sergio Peçanha, July 2023; Washington Post Company (Box Electronic Records)
  Profiles of Sergio Peçanha for the Washington Post. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Yan Wu, July 2023; Washington Post Company (Box Electronic Records)
  Profiles of Yan Wu for the Washington Post. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- West Side Federation for Senior and Supportive Housing, June 2020-July 2021; West Side Federation for Senior Housing (Box Electronic Records)
  West Side Federation For Senior and Supportive Housing, Inc. (WSFSSH) was formed in 1976 by a coalition of social service agencies, religious institutions, and community organizations. They work to meet the diverse needs of older people and persons living with special needs. Their first building, the Marseilles, opened in 1980 and provided 134 independent apartments to low income elderly and handicapped individuals. In addition to serving independent seniors, they now serve frail elderly individuals, older persons living with serious mental illnesses, homeless individuals, persons living with physically handicapping conditions, grandparents raising their grandchildren, and families. They currently house over 1,800 people in 24 buildings located on the Upper West Side, and in Harlem, Chelsea, and the Bronx.
- WSFSSH Locations, June 2020-July 2021; West Side Federation for Senior Housing (Box Electronic Records)
  Map of West Side Federation for Senior and Supportive Housing Locations.
- Pandemic Death Counts Are Numbing. There's Another Way to Process, July 2023; Wired (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Jacqueline Wernimont in Wired. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Workers Need Childcare, June 2020-January 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  Workers Need Childcare connects parents to free and low-cost childcare options during COVID-19. They rely on remote volunteers across the country, but their service is designed for parents in New York City's essential workforce (e.g. health care, education, shipping, media, warehousing, grocery and food production, utilities, domestic workers) who need affordable childcare options during COVID-19.
- Workers Need Childcare Flyer, June 2020-February 2022; Workers Need Childcare (Box Electronic Records)
  Flyer for the Workers Need Childcare organization.
- Workers Need Childcare Parent Volunteers Role Description, June 2020-February 2022; Workers Need Childcare (Box Electronic Records)
  Role descriptions for volunteers for the Workers Need Childcare organization.
- ARRIVALS+DEPARTURES, July 2023; YARA + DAVINA (Box Electronic Records)
  ARRIVALS+DEPARTURES is "an interactive public installation about birth, death and the journey in-between by YARA + DAVINA." A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Zip Code Memory Project, June 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
  The Zip Code Memory Project was a community-based project that sought ways to memorialize losses from the COVID-19 pandemic while also acknowledging its radically differential effects in Harlem, Washington Heights and the South Bronx neighborhoods. From Fall 2021 to Spring 2023, the organization carried out roundtable discussions; held the Imagine Repair Exhibition; held performances, presentations and other gatherings; and created a short film, Together, Not Alone. The website contains summarized reflections from discussions, videos of events, links to resources that informed the project, and information about organizers and partners.
- banging pots performance Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- BİRİM BADEMLI: Mapping Bodies in Concert Video, November 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
  During ZCMP workshops with Maria José Contreras, participants were asked to trace an outline of their bodies on a blank sheet, and mark that outline with the places where they feel the experience of COVID.
- Chronic Life: Can We Go the Distance With The Virus? Video, November 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Covid Sculpture 2 George Workshop Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Covid Sculpture George Workshop Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Fred Moten, "Prepare to Imagine" Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- George Emilio Sanchez "Land Acknowledgement" Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Imagine Repair performance outside cathedral Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Imani Uzuri Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Introduction to "Imagine Repair: Exhibition," at the Cathedral of St. John the Divine Video, November 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Maria Jose - Gesturing - Body Maps Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Maria Jose - NYC Maps Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Marie Howe, "The Singularity" Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Memorial Altar, "Imagine Repair: Exhibition," at the Cathedral of St. John the Divine Video, November 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Musical Performance- Amyra Leon - Imagine Repair Video, September 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Noni and Jordan- Zoom Collaborative Poems Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Noni Carter "Opening Remarks" Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Reparative Memory Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
  Artists and designers Michael Arad, Susan Meiselas, Doris Salcedo, Hank Willis Thomas, and Mabel O. Wilson each present their memorial projects. Introduced by Marianne Hirsch and Diana Taylor, Co-Directors of the Zip Code Memory Project. Moderated by Carol Becker, Dean of Columbia University School of the Arts. Co-presented by the Center for the Study of Social Difference; Columbia University School of the Arts; Columbia World Projects; The Forum; The Miriam and Ira D. Wallach Art Gallery; The Simon H. Rifkind Center for the Humanities & the Arts at the City College of New York; and The Society of Fellows and Heyman Center for the Humanities.
- Reparative Memory, Part II Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
  Part of a series of conversations on "Reparative Memory" in conjunction with Columbia University School of the Art's theme of "Repair" and the Zip Code Memory Project: Practices of Justice and Repair, based at the Center for the Study of Social Difference ​​with generous funding by the Henry Luce Foundation. Featuring María José Contreras Lorenzini, Rafael Lozano-Hemmer, and Kamau Ware. Introduced by Carol Becker, Dean of Columbia University School of the Arts. Moderated by Marianne Hirsch and Diana Taylor, Co-Directors of the Zip Code Memory Project.
- Reverend Billy and the Stop Shopping Choir Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Spirit Cards Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- The Reverend Juan Carlos Ruiz, "Tequio" Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- The Reverend Paul Anthony Daniels, II, "Welcome" Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Together, Not Alone Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Train the Trainers Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Why Zip Codes Video, September 2023; Zip Code Memory Project (Box Electronic Records)
- Coronavirus Resource Kit, June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. A general resource kit related to COVID.
- Protections against ICE Raids, June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. Resource list for migrants and undocumented immigrants related to ICE raids.